

Oviedo, Florida, USA

■ mollahsabbir@gmail.com | 🖸 mollahsabbir | 🛅 mollahsabbir | 📢 mollahsabbir

Summary.

A professional with expertise in Visual Language Models research and development. Highly versed in the intricacies of Linear Algebra and Statistics. Current research interest includes developing and improving unified VLM models. Currently working as a GRA at CRCV, UCF.

Education

University of Central Florida

Orlando, Florida, USA

2024 - Present

PHD IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Graduate Research Assistant at CRCV lab.
- Supervisor: Dr. Mubarak Shah

North South University

Dhaka, Bangladesh

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2017 - 2021

- Graduated with Magna Cum Laude distinction, CGPA 3.73/4.00.
- Thesis: Implemented **Domain Adaptation** on RawNet to train language invariant speaker recognition model.
- Experimented Image Colorization by implementing GAN models with different loss functions to gain bright colorized images.

Publications

ICPR 2022

M. I. Hossain, M. Rakib, S. Mollah, F. Rahman, and N. Mohammed, "LILA-BOTI: Leveraging Isolated Letter Accumulations By Ordering Teacher Insights for Bangla Handwriting Recognition," in arXiv preprint arXiv:2205.11420, 2022.

ICLR (Tiny Paper) 2023

Sabbir Mollah, Rakib Mohammed, Mashrur Wasek, AKM Shahariar Azad Rabby, Fuad Rahman, Nabeel Mohammed, "Automated Mapping of Healthcare Concepts to a Standardized Healthcare Taxonomy," in Proceedings of IEEE Conference or Journal Name, 2023, in Proceedings of IEEE Conference or Journal Name, 2023, Available: https://openreview.net/forum?id=87oCobKKS6x.

Experience _____

Machine Learning Engineer

Dhaka, Bangladesh

DEC 2022 - Present **BKASH LIMITED**

- Experimented with transformer based models to extract information from printed documents.
- Building fraud preventive system from graph database.
- Trained LSTM model to **predict missing address tokens**, e.g. missing postoffice.
- Designed comprehensive solution for English to Bangla machine transliteration.
- Built loan repayment model and completed loan risk assessment using Julia.
- Implemented backend features using Reactive Programming Paradigm to allow users to get human agent assisted services.

Software Engineer, Machine Learning

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Apurba Technologies Limited

SEP 2022 - DEC 2022

- Designed and developed Bangla Screen Reader, an accessibility application for visually impaired people.
- Developed NLP solution for mapping electronic health record against SNOMED Clinical Terminology.
- Developed an inter-encoding converter library for Bangla writings, implemented in Python, Java, C#, and Javascript.

Research Assistant Dhaka, Bangladesh APURBA-NSU R&D LAB

SEP 2021 - AUG 2022

- Used Knowledge Distillation to improve performance of CRNN model on minor classes.
- Trained MaskRCNN model to detect segments of Bangla documents.
- Worked on Bangla speech recognition.

Lab Instructor Dhaka, Bangladesh

ECE DEPARTMENT, NORTH SOUTH UNIVERSITY

Spring 2022 & Summer 2022

- Taught Database Management Systems (DBMS) using SQL and Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) using Java to an average class size of 40 students.
- Prepared lab materials and provided exam questions; examined students' answer scripts.

Skills

Machine Learning PyTorch, TensorFlow, Huggingface, scikit-learn, pandas, polars, pyspark and matplotlib.

Programming Python, Julia, Java, C, C++, C#, Julia, Haskell

Development Frameworks Flask, FastAPI, Spring Boot (Reactive), .Net Framework.

Database MySQL, DynamoDB, MongoDB, Neo4j

Version Controlling Git, GitHub, GitLab

Languages Bangla, English and Italian.

Volunteering Experience

NSU ACM Student Chapter

Dhaka, Bangladesh

2017 - 2021

CHAIR

• Elected as the Chapter Chair of this community of over 300 members.

Planned and organized HackNSU Season 2, an inter-university Hackathon with more than 25 participating teams.

NSU Communications Club

Dhaka, Bangladesh

 Sub Executive
 2017 - 2019

• Lead the Promotions team responsible for digital advertisement.

NSU Cultural ClubDhaka, Bangladesh

GENERAL MEMBER 2017 - 2019

• Helped the various artists in organizing on-campus cultural events.

Decorated campus during national and local festivities.

WorkshopsDhaka, Bangladesh

INSTRUCTOR 2020, 2021, 2022

• Instructed in 4 different workshops on Python, Pytorch, and deep learning

Atomic BAFSK Science Club

Dhaka, Bangladesh

FOUNDING GENERAL SECRETARY 2014 - 2016

• Took initiative in founding Science Club in secondary school

Achievements & Awards

Robi Datathon 2.0 Robi, Axiata Ltd., Dhaka

FINALISTS 2022

• Implemented cost sensitive learning to bump performance of a machine learning model

MIST Inter-University ICT Innovation Fest Hackathon

MIST, Dhaka

Designed and deployed a handwriting recognition model

IOT For Tomorrow NSU IEEE SB, Dhaka

FIRST RUNNERS-UP 2019

• Presented a fire detection circuit using a microcontroller integrated with Firebase

Electrathon NSU IEEE SB, Dhaka

2ND RUNNERS-UP 2018

• Solved various hardware and software related problems

Standardized Test Scores_

GRE: 329 Quantitative Reasoning: 170, Verbal Reasoning: 159, Analytical Writing: 4.0

IELTS: 8.0 Listening: 9.0, Reading: 7.5, Writing: 7.5, Speaking: 7.0